apples4theteacher.com 2014-07-02

# Apples4theteacher.com Privacy Polcy

Mission Statement

Effective 10/12/2013

Apples4theteacher.com  [owned and operated by Webstantaneous Web Marketing, LLC](http://www.webstantaneous.com/) was created to help teachers, homeschoolers and parents of school age children. Our mission is to provide free educational resources by thematic units. Almost all resources are printable and can be used in a classroom setting or at home to reinforce educational concepts.  [This privacy policy applies to our site www.apples4theteacher.com](http://www.apples4theteacher.com/). 

[Apples4theteacher.com](http://www.apples4theteacher.com/) has received TRUSTe's Privacy and Children’s Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy statement and our practices have been reviewed for compliance with the TRUSTe program viewable on the validation page available by clicking the TRUSTe seal. The TRUSTe program only covers information collected on this site [www.apples4theteacher.com](http://www.apples4theteacher.com/). 

If you have questions or concerns regarding our privacy policy or practices, please contact us at [privacy@apples4theteacher.com](mailto:privacy@apples4theteacher.com). If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact TRUSTe at[ https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request](https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request). 

**Privacy of Children Online  
**We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 13. If we learn that we have personal information on a child under the age of 13, we will delete that information from our systems **immediately**. Apples4theteacher.com encourages parents to go online with their kids. Here are a few tips to help make a child's online experience safer: 

  * Teach kids never to give personal information, unless supervised by a parent or responsible adult. Includes name, address, phone, school, etc. 
  * Know the sites your kids are visiting and which sites are appropriate. 
  * If your child uses social media sites and mobile devices - review the privacy settings for your child's safety. 
  * Look for website privacy policies. Know how your child's information is treated. 

Check out the FTC's site at <http://www.consumer.ftc.gov/topics/kids-online-safety> for more tips on protecting your child online.

We respect the privacy of our users and the concerns of parents for their children visiting our site. We strive to be in compliance with the policies of "COPPA" (the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act) and provide this page to make users aware of our website's policy on privacy:

  1. Consent to Privacy Policy
  2. Use of Photos or Videos with Children in Them
  3. Collection Information - Analytics
  4. Advertisers
  5. Social Plugins
  6. Newsletter
  7. Opt-Out Options
  8. Contact Us
  9. Access to Personal Information
  10. Changes in this Privacy Policy
  11. Security
  12. Sharing of Information
  13. Links to Other Sites

**1\. Consent to Privacy Policy**   
By providing Apples4theteacher.com with Personal Information (such as your email address), you signify that you agree with the terms of our current Privacy Policy as posted here. If you do not agree with any term in this policy, please look at opt-out options listed below or refrain from using our website as per our Terms of Service.

**2\. Use of Photos or Videos with Children in Them  
**No photos or videos associated with Apples4theteacher.com show children under the age of 13 without parental permission. Users are not allowed to post photos or videos to the website or social media sites associated with Apples4theteacher.com. **  
**

**3\. Collection of Information - Analytics  
** Site measurement statistics may be used to personalize your website experience, as well as to evaluate - anonymously and in the aggregate \- statistics about usage of the web site. Information about your computer, such as your IP address (a number assigned to your computer whenever you surf the Internet), the type of Internet browser you are using and the type of computer operating system you are using may also be collected. 

"Cookies" are files or pieces of information that are stored by your browser on your computer’s hard drive. Apples4theteacher.com does not collect more personally identifiable information than necessary to participate in any of the site's activities. Cookies are an effective information resource and they ensure that our web site presents the best web experience for new and returning visitors.

The use of cookies by third parties is not covered by our privacy policy. We do not have access or control over these cookies. 

Clear Gifs (Web Beacons)

We employ or our third party tracking utility partner employs a software technology called clear gifs (a.k.a web beacons), that help us better manage content on our site by informing us what content is effective. Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of Web users. In contrast to cookies, which are stored on a user’s computer hard drive, clear gifs are embedded invisibly on Web pages and are about the size of the period at the end of this sentence. We do not tie the information gathered by clear gifs to our customers’ personal information. 

Site Analytics Privacy Policies:

**4\. Advertisers**  
Apples4theteacher.com has offered free teaching resources since 1999. We have been able to offer our resources for free because ad networks pay us for advertising space on resource pages. While viewing our website, a third party advertiser may place a cookie in your browser. You may view the privacy policy of each ad network that Apples4theteacher.com works with below:

  * Netseer

Teacher resource pages may have additional ad code from the following ad networks. We are in the process of removing ad code on our pages (that are geared towards children such as our game pages and interactive puzzles) from the following ad networks. In the event that we missed some code, their privacy policies can be found here via the associated link. Please feel free to opt out of their advertising and [notify us](mailto:privacy@apples4theteacher.com) what page the ad code appeared on, so we may change the code.

**5\. Social Plugins**  
Our Web site includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button and Widgets, such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it. 

**6\. Newsletter**  
Your privacy is important to us. We do not share your email with any 3rd party. Our newsletters may be sponsored by trusted third parties. Though you may receive an email from us on behalf of our sponsor, our sponsors do not have direct access to your email. You may unsubscribe from our list at any time if you don't find our mailings helpful. You are given the option to manage your subscription directly from every newsletter or you may request information be removed from our mailing list by emailing us at [news@apples4theteacher-news.com](mailto:news@apples4theteacher-news.com).

We do not knowingly collect information from children under the age of 13. If we see that we have information from children under the age of 13, we delete that information. If a child under the age of 13 signs up for the newsletter (without our knowledge), parents can request that a child's information be removed from our database by sending an email to [news@apples4theteacher-news.com](mailto:news@apples4theteacher-news.com).

**7\. Opt-Out Options**  
Apples4theteacher.com's mission is to keep our educational resources free for our visitors. Opting out of advertising puts our mission at risk (meaning we may have to charge for our resources to cover operating costs). However, we respect all visitors views on privacy and offer the following opt-out options.  
**Note: Some website features may break if you choose to opt-out of tracking.**

To opt out of analytics tracking:

To opt out of non-contextual advertising:

**8\. Contact Us**  
Questions or concerns over our privacy policy? 

Contact:  
Webstantaneous Web Marketing, LLC  
c/o Judy Miller - President/CEO  
PO Box 11334   
Chandler, AZ 85248 

or email [privacy@apples4theteacher.com](mailto:privacy@apples4theteacher.com)

**9\. Access to Personal Information**  
If your personal information changes or you no longer desire our service, you may update, delete inaccuracies, or modify your information by contacting us at privacy@apples4theteacher.com. We will respond to your access request within 30 days.

We will retain your information for as long as needed to provide you services. If you wish to request that we no longer use your information to provide you services, you may contact us at the email address listed above. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

**10\. Changes in this Privacy Policy**  
We may update this privacy statement to reflect changes to our information practices. If we make any material changes we will notify you by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this Site prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.   

**11\. Security**  
The security of your personal information is important to us. We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. 

**12\. Sharing of Information**   
We will share your personal information with third parties only in ways that are described in this privacy policy. We do not sell your personal information to third parties.

We may provide your personal information to companies that provide services to help us with our business activities such as sending out newsletters on our behalf or offering customer service. These companies are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services to us.

We may also disclose your personal information as required by law, such as to comply with a subpoena, or similar legal process; when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request. 

If we are involved in a merger or acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of our assets, you will be notified via email and/or prominent notice on our Web site of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information. 

**13\. Links**  
This Web site contains links to other sites that are not owned or controlled by us. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites.

We encourage you to be aware when you leave our site and to read the privacy policies of each and every Web site that collects personal information.

This privacy policy applies only to information collected by this Web site. 

This privacy policy was update on or about October 15, 2013.
